<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Guilherme Lyra</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Guilherme Lyra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 14:07:09 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minha Jornada ao CCIE</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/jornada-ccie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 14:07:09 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/jornada-ccie/</guid>
      <description>Oficialmente comecei minha carreira em TI em 2006, mas, meus primeiros passos com redes ocorreram alguns anos antes disso, entre 2002 e 2003.
Em 2006 comecei como estagiário no suporte a usuários em um órgão do governo. Comecei formatando computadores e progredi rapidamente até um ponto em que lidava com toda a infraestrutrua de rede incluindo switches, firewalls, proxy, file servers, AD, etc.
Após finalizar esse estágio, fui para outra empresa, novamente como estagiário, onde passei mais 2 anos antes de ser oficialmente contratado.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS XE Model-Driven Telemetry</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/ios-xe-telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 14:07:09 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/ios-xe-telemetry/</guid>
      <description>There is a ton of content available on Cisco DevNet explaining Model-Driven Telemetry theory in great detail, so I highly suggest you take some time to browse through the links I&amp;rsquo;ve listed under the Reference of this post.
Summary My lab router is a Cisco ISR C1111-4G running IOS XE 17.6.3a. The same environment can be set up on a CSR1000v or Catalyst 8000v running on Cisco CML for example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Community Live Event - Cisco SD-WAN</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/cisco-community-sdwan-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 14:07:09 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cisco-community-sdwan-event/</guid>
      <description>In November 2020 I had the honor of being invited by Cisco Community to present a live event about Cisco SD-WAN (Viptela). The event had more than 300 participants, from 9 different countries.
For those who want to know more about this excellent Cisco solution, the recording is available on the link below (presentation language is Brazilian Portuguese).
Watch the video on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xtTHjDv1r-M</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
